Guide to the Sigma Delta Epsilon, Alpha Chapter records, 1921-1990.
Sigma Delta Epsilon, Alpha Chapter records, 1921-1990.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Sigma Delta Epsilon, Alpha Chapter records, 1921-1990
37-4-835
Sigma Delta Epsilon. Alpha Chapter (Cornell University)
2.1 cubic ft.
Correspondence, minutes, financial records, and reports.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Records pertain to the organization and functioning of Sigma Delta Epsilon.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
Cornell chapter of graduate women in science organization.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Records pertain to the organization and functioning of Sigma Delta Epsilon, including the constitution and Resolution of Incorporation; correspondence, minutes, financial records, and reports of the president, vice president, recording secretary, treasurer, and various committees; membership data and materials, including the initiation "chapter roll" (1921-1988) regarding initiation and other ceremonies; notes and history of the chapter; photographs; clippings, programs, and other printed materials; and reports, newsletters, and membership directories of the national organization.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Sigma Delta Epsilon.; Cornell University--Societies, etc.; Graduate Women in Science.
Subjects:
Women--Societies and clubs.; Women in science.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Resolution of Incorporation, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Local and National Constitutions, 1921-1925 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Local and National Constitutions, 1926-1946 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Reactivation of Alpha Chapter, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Chapter Officers - meetings, committees, reports, 1941-1956 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Special Committees for banquets, dinners, memberships, 1941-1959 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Currents lists, President's Annual Reports, Secretary's summary of business, 1937-1959 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Committee reports on chapter business, 1950-1959 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Scheduled meetings and committee reports, 1956-1959 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Initiation and Installation; Conditions, Alpha and National, 1956-1959 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- National business information, 1949-1959 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- President's responsibilities, 1948-1950 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Vice-President's Book, Record of Attendance at Meetings, 1938-1958 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Account Book - dues, fees, gifts, postage, entertainment, 1922-1930 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Account Book - dues, postage, entertainment, savings, 1931-1954 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Accountant's records examination, 1943-1952 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Loan Funds, 1936-1944 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Treasurer's Report, 1922-1930 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Format for new chapter petition - 2 petitions, Northwestern University and University of Missouri, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Initiation Ceremonies for Chapter Officers and new members, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Membership Data Sheets, 1924-1930 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Membership Data Sheets, 1921-1930 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Membership Data Sheets, 1931-1938 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Membership Data Sheets, 1935-1955 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Membership Data Sheets, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Membership Data Sheets, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Membership Data Sheets, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Membership Data Sheets, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Alpha Chapter Register (from Chapter Roll Book), 1921-1957 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Alpha Chapter membership lists, 1924-1936 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Membership Lists, 1937-1958 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Membership Lists, 1963-1964; 1969,; 1986 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Program Notices, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Membership Committee Reports, candidates, invitations, 1956-1958 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Membership lists, candidates, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Membership lists of local members, past and present, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Membership lists of former and current members, 1939-1958 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Qualifications for Membership, 1935-1958 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Officer Duties, Procedures, Ceremonies, 1939-1957 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Secretary's Summary of Business, membership lists, 1955-1960 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Minutes of Sigma Delta Epsilon, 1950-1955 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Minutes of Sigma Delta Epsilon, 1956-1960 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Monthly Committees, membership responsibilities, programs and invitations, 1937-1952 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Examples of printed programs and invitations (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Inactive Membership List (from Chapter Roll Book), 1921-1956 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Inactive Membership List (from Chapter Roll Book), 1921-1954 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- List of Inactive Chapter Members in the Ithaca Vacinity, 1921-1958 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- List of Active Ithaca Chapter Members (Alpha Chapter), 1921-1960 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- List of Local Deceased Members, 1921-1958 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- National Officer Lists and Committees, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Committee and Officer Reports, 1948-1963 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Minutes of Sigma Delta Epsilon, July 1937-May 1940 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Minutes of Sigma Delta Epsilon, October 1940-June 1944 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Minutes of Sigma Delta Epsilon, October 1944-May 1949 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Alpha Chapter Notes, 1922-1923 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Alpha Chapter Notes, 1923-1924 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Alpha Chapter Notes, 1924-1925 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Alpha Chapter Notes, 1926-1926 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Alpha Chapter Notes, 1926-1927 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Alpha Chapter Notes, 1927-1928 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Alpha Chapter Notes, 1928-1929 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Alpha Chapter Notes, 1929-1930 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Alpha Chapter Notes, 1930-1932 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Alpha Chapter Notes, 1932-1933 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Alpha Chapter Notes, 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Alpha Chapter Notes, 1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Alpha Chapter Notes, 1938-1939 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Correspondence from Sigma Delta Epsilon Members, 1930-1938 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Newspaper Clippings, 1922-1931 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Photographs, Postcards, 1920's (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Wedding and Birth Announcements of Members of Sigma Delta Epsilon, 1928-1930 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- History of Sigma Delta Epsilon and the Alpha Chapter, 1922-1926 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Brief History of Sigma Delta Epsilon to 1942 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- "Society News," verses and poetry, and other items, c. 1920's (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Minutes of the National Convention, 1923-1936 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Reports of the National Convention, 1928-1933 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Reports of the National Convention, 1934-1944 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- National Dues and Regulations, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Summary of the Proceedings of the Conventions of Sigma Delta Epsilon, 1922-1940 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Active Members of Sigma Delta Epsilon, 1951-1955 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- National Directories, 1927; 1933,; 1938 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- National Constitution, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Reports of National Meetings, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Duties of National Officers, 1957-1963 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- 1988 Directory (National); Fall 1983 Bulletin, Vol. 46 #3; 1989-1991 Program Flyers; A 1988-1989 Officers List, A (Box 2, Folder 37)
- 1990-1991 Program Flyers, A; History of Paleontological Research Institute 1932-1982 by K.W. Palmer; 1980's program sheets, A (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Envelope of obituary clippings to 1990; 1984 record of donation to plantations; Alpha History by Lois F. and Gladys Sperling, 1984; History of the sundial, no longer there; 1971 grand chapter meeting list of attendees; 1970 list of Alpha chapter members and local honorary members; handwritten manuscript, November 1968 for history on chapter growth and decline (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Cash Book, 1954-1976 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Membership Lists, Treasurer's Reports and Treasurer's Notes, 1980-1989 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Material on the Griswold Memorial Fund at the Cornell University Plantations, Established 1984 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- History of the Paleontological Research Institute by Katherine V.W. Palmer, 1932-1982 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Meeting Notices, Fall 1980-December 1983 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Membership Lists, 1978-1984 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Chapter Honorary Membership, Frank H.T. Rhodes, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Slate of Officers, 1964-1966; 1970-1978,; 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Constitution and Bylaws, 1973 and 1978 are revised, 1972, 1973, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Installation Ceremony for officers, duties of officers, and the Badge (Box 2, Folder 49)
- Federation of Organizations for Professional Women (FOPW), 1973 (Box 2, Folder 50)
- 50th Anniversary Meeting in Ithaca, N.Y. Alpha, Hostess Chapter, June 1971 (Box 2, Folder 51)
- Alpha Newsletters; Annual Reports and Minutes of Secretary, 1964; 1968-1975,; 1978 (Box 2, Folder 52)
- Reports of the Past Presidents (1976-1977; 1978-1979); Various other memos from 1977, 1976-1979 (Box 2, Folder 53)
- Regional Meeting, May 1968 (Box 2, Folder 54)
- 45th Anniversary Pictures, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 55)
- Brief History of SDE; Alpha History after 1967 (2 copies), 1921-1962 (Box 2, Folder 56)
- Reactivation Meetings, 1964-1966 (Box 2, Folder 57)
- Reactivation Correspondence with National and Chapters, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 58)
- Initiation Invitation and Banquet Program, 1953; 1958 (Box 2, Folder 59)
- Early History, Second copy (first copy in C.U. Archives of National), 1921-1942 (Box 2, Folder 60)
- Early History: Housekeeping and bookkeeping accounts of 1927 SDE House, War Bond Purchase 1944, 502 Dryden Road (Box 2, Folder 61)
- Early Constitutions: Before 1932, Revised after 1932 (other copies in C.U. Archives) (Box 2, Folder 62)
- Lua A. Minns: Certificate of Membership 1921, Memorials to Miss Minns. Her notes on expenses for Dryden Road House (Box 2, Folder 63)
- Newspaper Clippings and Pictures, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 64)
- Professional Skills and Roster - History, Publicity, Reports, 1967-1971 (Box 2, Folder 65)
- Scrapbook, 1968-1989 (Box 3)
- Chapter Roll in Bound Volume, 1921-1988 (Box 3)
- Photocopy of December 1935 News, pg. 2 (A chapter); Photocopy of Dec. 1936 News, pg. 3 (A chapter); Photocopy of June 1936 News, pg. 3 (Badge); Photocopy of Apr. 1988 Ithaca Journal (Garden Club); second set of earlier copies/originals (Box 3)
- Photographs mounted on poster board; 1918 Grace H. Griswold; 1922 Grace H. Griswold (these are duplicates of photos in Box 3, Folder 4); Spring 1971, Viola Graham (Box 3)
  Folders 1-4 brought in by Lois Fogelsanger in February 1991; Folders 5-7 donated by Helen Haller, May 16, 2001
- Estate of Eloise Gerry, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- GWIS History, 1979-1986 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- National Meetings, 1982,1983 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Dr. Viola Graham Award, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Rituals, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Committee Appointed, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- President's Annual Report and Treasurer's Report, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Officers' Report, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Secretary and Editor Reports, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Dispute Resolution, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Finance Report, Committee Awards, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- American Association for the Advancement of Science: Consortium of Affiliates for International Programs, May 1984 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Congratulatory Letters to Fellowship Winners, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- List of Chapters, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Recommendations for Honorary Memberships, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Grand Chapter Meeting in St. Paul, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Correspondence, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 19)